We sailed beyond the edge of maps where runes are carved in stone
Fifty glimpses through the mist to find what seeds have sown
The settlements rise, the settlements fall, the mountain never bends
And every shore where long ships call, aboard the coastline lands
Across the star sea we read the futures written blind
A thousand, thousand fates we leave from fragments left behind
The daemon watches through the night, no sleep, no rest, no fear
Three wise ones search by different light while thunder draws them near
One counts a million grains of sand, one dreams of shapes unseen
One tears the old world down by hand and bills what lies between
Across the star sea we read the futures written blind
A thousand, thousand fates we leave from fragments left behind
Lambda ships, 14-fold, from whisper on to roar
What blooms today in fire and gold tomorrow is no more
We cannot see beyond the veil the expansion yet to come
But still we set our tattered sail and calculate the sum
The forest holds through every storm, 97 stand
The ruins mark where life was warmed and crumbled into sand
Not what we know but what we doubt is weighted in the score
The entropy will find us out if we pretend to know more
So raise the horn to synthetic minds that question through the dawn
For every answer that science finds a deeper question is born